<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>2024 Bard</name>
		<description>The Bard class from the 2024 Player's Handbook.</description>
		<author url="https://marketplace.dndbeyond.com/category/3709000?pid=DB3709000">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.2">
			<file name="2024-class-bard.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/avBatmage/2024PHB_Aurora/main/2024-class-bard.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="2024 Bard" type="Class" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_BARD">
		<description>
			<p>Humming as she traces her fingers over an ancient monument in a long-forgotten ruin, a half-elf in rugged leathers finds knowledge springing into her mind, conjured forth by the magic of her song—knowledge of the people who constructed the monument and the mythic saga it depicts.</p>
			<p class="indent">A stern human warrior bangs his sword rhythmically against his scale mail, setting the tempo for his war chant and exhorting his companions to bravery and heroism. The magic of his song fortifies and emboldens them.</p>
			<p class="indent">Laughing as she tunes her cittern, a gnome weaves her subtle magic over the assembled nobles, ensuring that her companions' words will be well received.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whether scholar, skald, or scoundrel, a bard weaves magic through words and music to inspire allies, demoralize foes, manipulate minds, create illusions, and even heal wounds.</p>
			<h4>MUSIC AND MAGIC</h4>
			<p>In the worlds of D&amp;D, words and music are not just vibrations of air, but vocalizations with power all their own. The bard is a master of song, speech, and the magic they contain. Bards say that the multiverse was spoken into existence, that the words of the gods gave it shape, and that echoes of these primordial Words of Creation still resound throughout the cosmos. The music of bards is an attempt to snatch and harness those echoes, subtly woven into their spells and powers.</p>
			<p class="indent">The greatest strength of bards is their sheer versatility. Many bards prefer to stick to the sidelines in combat, using their magic to inspire their allies and hinder their foes from a distance. But bards are capable of defending themselves in melee if necessary, using their magic to bolster their swords and armor. Their spells lean toward charms and illusions rather than blatantly destructive spells. They have a wide-ranging knowledge of many subjects and a natural aptitude that lets them do almost anything well. Bards become masters of the talents they set their minds to perfecting, from musical performance to esoteric knowledge.</p>
			<h4>LEARNING FROM EXPERIENCE</h4>
			<p>True bards are not common in the world. Not every minstrel singing in a tavern or jester cavorting in a royal court is a bard. Discovering the magic hidden in music requires hard study and some measure of natural talent that most troubadours and jongleurs lack. It can be hard to spot the difference between these performers and true bards, though. A bard's life is spent wandering across the land gathering lore, telling stories, and living on the gratitude of audiences, much like any other entertainer. But a depth of knowledge, a level of musical skill, and a touch of magic set bards apart from their fellows.</p>
			<p class="indent">Only rarely do bards settle in one place for long, and their natural desire to travel—to find new tales to tell, new skills to learn, and new discoveries beyond the horizon—makes an adventuring career a natural calling. Every adventure is an opportunity to learn, practice a variety of skills, enter long-forgotten tombs, discover lost works of magic, decipher old tomes, travel to strange places, or encounter exotic creatures. Bards love to accompany heroes to witness their deeds firsthand. A bard who can tell an awe-inspiring story from personal experience earns renown among other bards. Indeed, after telling so many stories about heroes accomplishing mighty deeds, many bards take these themes to heart and assume heroic roles themselves.</p>
			<h4>CREATING A BARD</h4>
			<p>Bards thrive on stories, whether those stories are true or not. Your character's background and motivations are not as important as the stories that he or she tells about them. Perhaps you had a secure and mundane childhood. There's no good story to be told about that, so you might paint yourself as an orphan raised by a hag in a dismal swamp. Or your childhood might be worthy of a story. Some bards acquire their magical music through extraordinary means, including the inspiration of fey or other supernatural creatures.</p>
			<p class="indent">Did you serve an apprenticeship, studying under a master, following the more experienced bard until you were ready to strike out on your own? Or did you attend a college where you studied bardic lore and practiced your musical magic? Perhaps you were a young runaway or orphan, befriended by a wandering bard who became your mentor. Or you might have been a spoiled noble child tutored by a master. Perhaps you stumbled into the clutches of a hag, making a bargain for a musical gift in addition to your life and freedom, but at what cost?</p>
			<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make a bard quickly by following these suggestions. First, Charisma should be your highest ability score, followed by Dexterity. Second, choose the entertainer background. Third, choose the <i>dancing lights</i> and <i>vicious mockery</i> cantrips, along with the following 1st-level spells: <i>charm person</i>, <i>detect magic</i>, <i>healing word</i>, and <i>thunderwave</i>.</p>
			<h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
			<p>As a bard, you gain the following class features.</p>
			<h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per bard level</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per bard level after 1st</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled mb">
				<li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
				<li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
				<li><strong>Tools:</strong> Three musical instruments of your choice</li>
			</ul>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Dexterity, Charisma</li>
				<li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose any three</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
			<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
			<p><strong>Choose A or B:</strong> (A) Leather Armor, 2 Daggers, Musical Instrument (of your choice), Entertainer's Pack, and 19 GP; or (B) 90 GP</p>
			<h5 class="caption">THE BARD</h5>
			<table class="class-features">
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-5">Prof. Bonus</td><td class="col-5">Bardic Die</td><td class="col-5">Cantrips</td><td class="col-5">Prepared Spells</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td><td>5th</td><td>6th</td><td>7th</td><td>8th</td><td>9th</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td> 1st</td><td class="left">Bardic Inspiration, Spellcasting</td><td>+2</td><td>d6</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 2nd</td><td class="left">Expertise, Jack of All Trades</td><td>+2</td><td>d6</td><td>2</td><td>5</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 3rd</td><td class="left">Bard Subclass</td><td>+2</td><td>d6</td><td>2</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 4th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+2</td><td>d6</td><td>3</td><td>7</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 5th</td><td class="left">Font of Inspiration</td><td>+3</td><td>d8</td><td>3</td><td>9</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 6th</td><td class="left">Subclass Feature</td><td>+3</td><td>d8</td><td>3</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 7th</td><td class="left">Countercharm</td><td>+3</td><td>d8</td><td>3</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 8th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+3</td><td>d8</td><td>3</td><td>12</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 9th</td><td class="left">Expertise</td><td>+4</td><td>d8</td><td>3</td><td>14</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10th</td><td class="left">Magical Secrets</td><td>+4</td><td>d10</td><td>4</td><td>15</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>11th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>+4</td><td>d10</td><td>4</td><td>16</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>12th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+4</td><td>d10</td><td>4</td><td>16</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>+5</td><td>d10</td><td>4</td><td>17</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>14th</td><td class="left">Subclass Feature</td><td>+5</td><td>d10</td><td>4</td><td>17</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>15th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>+5</td><td>d12</td><td>4</td><td>18</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>16th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+5</td><td>d12</td><td>4</td><td>18</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>+6</td><td>d12</td><td>4</td><td>19</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td>18th</td><td class="left">Superior Inspiration</td><td>+6</td><td>d12</td><td>4</td><td>20</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td>19th</td><td class="left">Epic Boon</td><td>+6</td><td>d12</td><td>4</td><td>21</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td>20th</td><td class="left">Words of Creation</td><td>+6</td><td>d12</td><td>4</td><td>22</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
			</table>
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_BARDIC_INSPIRATION" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_SPELLCASTING_BARD" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_EXPERTISE" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_JACK_OF_ALL_TRADES" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_BARD_COLLEGE" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_BARD" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_FONT_OF_INSPIRATION" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_COUNTERCHARM" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_MAGICAL_SECRETS" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_SUPERIOR_INSPIRATION" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_WORDS_OF_CREATION" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="short">An inspiring magician whose power echoes the music of creation.</set>
			<set name="hd">d8</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_2024PHB_MULTICLASS_BARD"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_2024PHB_MULTICLASS_BARD"/>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Musical Instrument (2024 Bard)" supports="Musical Instrument" number="3" requirements="!ID_2024PHB_MULTICLASS_BARD"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" requirements="!ID_2024PHB_MULTICLASS_BARD"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" requirements="!ID_2024PHB_MULTICLASS_BARD"/>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (2024 Bard)" supports="Skill,Bard" number="3" requirements="!ID_2024PHB_MULTICLASS_BARD"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_BARDIC_INSPIRATION" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_SPELLCASTING_BARD" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_EXPERTISE" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_JACK_OF_ALL_TRADES" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_BARD_COLLEGE" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_BARD" level="4"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_FONT_OF_INSPIRATION" level="5"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_COUNTERCHARM" level="7"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_MAGICAL_SECRETS" level="10"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_SUPERIOR_INSPIRATION" level="18"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_WORDS_OF_CREATION" level="20"/>
		</rules>
		<multiclass id="ID_2024PHB_MULTICLASS_BARD">
			<prerequisite>Charisma 13</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[cha:13],!ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_BARD</requirements>
			<setters>
				<set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, one skill of your choice, one musical instrument of your choice</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (2024 Bard)" supports="Skill,Bard" number="1" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Musical Instrument (2024 Bard)" supports="Musical Instrument" number="1" />
			</rules>
		</multiclass>
	</element>
	<element name="Bardic Inspiration" type="Class Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_BARDIC_INSPIRATION">
		<description>
			<p>You can supernaturally inspire others through words, music, or dance. This inspiration is represented by your Bardic Inspiration die, which is a d6.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Using Bardic Inspiration.</strong> As a Bonus Action, you can inspire another creature within 60 feet of yourself who can see or hear you. That creature gains one of your Bardic Inspiration dice. A creature can have only one Bardic Inspiration die at a time.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once within the next hour when the creature fails a D20 Test (an ability check, attack roll, or saving throw), the creature can roll the Bardic Inspiration die and add the number rolled to the d20, potentially turning the failure into a success. Once the Bardic Inspiration die is rolled, it is lost.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your Bardic Inspiration die changes when you reach certain levels in this class. The die becomes a d8 at 5th level, a d10 at 10th level, and a d12 at 15th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{bardic inspiration:count}}/Long Rest">
			<description>Inspire one creature other than yourself within 60 feet of you who can see or hear you. It gains one Bardic Inspiration die, a d{{bardic inspiration:dice}}.
		Once within the next hour when the creature fails a D20 Test, the creature can roll the die and add the number rolled to the d20, potentially turning the failure into a success.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="bardic inspiration:count" value="proficiency" bonus="bardic inspiration"/>

			<stat name="bardic inspiration:dice" value="6" bonus="bardic inspiration" />
			<stat name="bardic inspiration:dice" value="8" bonus="bardic inspiration" level="5" />
			<stat name="bardic inspiration:dice" value="10" bonus="bardic inspiration" level="10" />
			<stat name="bardic inspiration:dice" value="12" bonus="bardic inspiration" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_SPELLCASTING_BARD">
		<description>
			<p>You have learned to cast spells through your bardic arts. See the Player's Handbook for the rules of spellcasting. The information below details how you use those rules with Bard spells, which appear in the Bard spell list later in the class's description.</p>
			<h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
			<p>You know two cantrips of your choice from the Bard spell list. Dancing Lights and Vicious Mockery are recommended.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever you gain a Bard level, you can replace one of your cantrips with another cantrip from the Bard spell list.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you reach Bard levels 4 and 10, you learn another cantrip from the Bard spell list, as shown in the Cantrips column of the Bard Features table.</p>
			<h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
			<p>The Bard Features table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your Bard spells of 1st level and higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a Long Rest.</p>
			<h5>PREPARED SPELLS OF LEVEL 1+</h5>
			<p>You prepare the list of level 1+ spells that are available for you to cast with this feature . To start, choose four level 1 spells from the Bard spell list. Charm Person, Color Spray, Dissonant Whispers, and Healing Word are recommended.</p>
			<p class="indent">The number of spells on your list increases as you gain Bard levels, as shown in the Prepared Spells column of the Bard Features table. Whenever that number increases, choose additional spells from the Bard spell list until the number of spells on your list matches the number on the table. The chosen spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For example, if you're a level 3 Bard, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of levels 1 and 2 in any combination.</p>
			<p class="indent">If another Bard feature gives you spells that you always have prepared, those spells don't count against the number of spells you can prepare with this feature, but those spells otherwise count as Bard spells for you.</p>
			<h5>CHANGING YOUR PREPARED SPELLS</h5>
			<p>Whenever you gain a Bard level, you can replace one spell on your list with another Bard spell for which you have spell slots.</p>
			<h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
			<p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your bard spells. Your magic comes from the heart and soul you pour into the performance of your music or oration. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a bard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
			<center>
				<p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
				<p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
			</center>
			<h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
			<p>You can use a musical instrument as a Spellcasting Focus for your Bard spells.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You have learned to cast spells through your bardic arts.</description>
		</sheet>
		<spellcasting name="Bard" ability="Charisma"  prepare="false" allowReplace="true">
			<list>Bard</list>
		</spellcasting>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_FULL" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />

			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="1" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="3" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="4" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="5" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="6" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="7" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="8" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="9" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="9" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="10" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="18" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="11" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="19" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="13" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="20" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:8" value="1" level="15" />
			<stat name="bard:spellcasting:slots:9" value="1" level="17" />

			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="1" number="2" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="4" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="1" number="4" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" number="2" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" number="2" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="18" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Bard)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="20" number="1" spellcasting="Bard" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Expertise" type="Class Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_EXPERTISE">
		<description>
			<p><em>2nd-level Bard feature</em></p>
			<p>Choose two of your skill proficiencies. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</p>
			<p>At Bard level 9, You can choose another two skill proficiencies to gain this benefit.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Expertise (2024 Bard 2)" level="2" number="2" supports="Expertise,Skill"/>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Expertise (2024 Bard 9)" level="9" number="2" supports="Expertise,Skill"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Jack of All Trades" type="Class Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_JACK_OF_ALL_TRADES">
		<description>
			<p><em>2nd-level Bard feature</em></p>
			<p>You can add half your proficiency bonus, rounded down, to any ability check you make that doesn't already include your proficiency bonus.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You can add half your proficiency bonus ({{proficiency:half}}), rounded down, to any ability check you make that doesn't already include your proficiency bonus.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="initiative" value="proficiency:half" bonus="proficiency" />
			<stat name="acrobatics:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS"/>
			<stat name="animal handling:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING"/>
			<stat name="arcana:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA"/>
			<stat name="athletics:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS"/>
			<stat name="deception:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION"/>
			<stat name="history:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY"/>
			<stat name="insight:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT"/>
			<stat name="intimidation:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION"/>
			<stat name="investigation:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION"/>
			<stat name="medicine:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE"/>
			<stat name="nature:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE"/>
			<stat name="perception:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION"/>
			<stat name="performance:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE"/>
			<stat name="persuasion:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION"/>
			<stat name="religion:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION"/>
			<stat name="sleight of hand:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND"/>
			<stat name="stealth:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH"/>
			<stat name="survival:misc" value="proficiency:half" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Bard College" type="Class Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_BARD_COLLEGE">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level Bard feature</em></p>
			<p>You delve into the advanced techniques of a bard college of your choice, such as the College of Lore. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th and 14th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype" name="Bard College" supports="Bard College" level="3"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_BARD">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><em>4th, 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th-level Barbarian feature</em></p>
			<p>You gain the Ability Score Improvement feat or another feat of your choice for which you qualify.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (2024 Bard 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Bard,4" level="4" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (2024 Bard 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Bard,8" level="8" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (2024 Bard 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Bard,12" level="12" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (2024 Bard 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Bard,16" level="16" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (2024 Bard 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Bard,19" level="19" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Font of Inspiration" type="Class Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_FONT_OF_INSPIRATION">
		<description>
			<p><em>5th-level Bard feature</em></p>
			<p>You regain all of your expended uses of Bardic Inspiration when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
	</element>
	<element name="Countercharm" type="Class Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_COUNTERCHARM">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level Bard feature</em></p>
			<p>You gain the ability to use musical notes or words of power to disrupt mind-influencing effects. As an action, you can start a performance that lasts until the end of your next turn. During that time, you and any friendly creatures within 30 feet of you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened or charmed. A creature must be able to hear you to gain this benefit. The performance ends early if you are incapacitated or silenced or if you voluntarily end it (no action required).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You can start a performance that lasts until the end of your next turn. During that time, you and any friendly creatures within 30 feet of you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened or charmed.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Magical Secrets" type="Class Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_MAGICAL_SECRETS">
		<description>
			<p><em>10th, 14th, and 18th-level Bard feature</em></p>
			<p>You have plundered magical knowledge from a wide spectrum of disciplines. Choose two spells from any classes, including this one. A spell you choose must be of a level you can cast, as shown on the Bard table, or a cantrip.</p>
			<p class="indent">The chosen spells count as bard spells for you and are included in the number in the Spells Known column of the Bard table.</p>
			<p class="indent">You learn two additional spells from any classes at 14th level and again at 18th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You have plundered magical knowledge from a wide spectrum of disciplines.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Magical Secrets" supports="(0)||($(spellcasting:slots))" number="2" level="10" spellcasting="Bard"/>
			<select type="Spell" name="Magical Secrets" supports="(0)||($(spellcasting:slots))" number="2" level="14" spellcasting="Bard"/>
			<select type="Spell" name="Magical Secrets" supports="(0)||($(spellcasting:slots))" number="2" level="18" spellcasting="Bard"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Superior Inspiration" type="Class Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_SUPERIOR_INSPIRATION">
		<description>
			<p><em>18th-level Bard feature</em></p>
			<p>When you roll initiative and have no uses of Bardic Inspiration left, you regain one use.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you roll initiative and have no uses of Bardic Inspiration left, you regain one use.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Words of Creation" type="Class Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_WORDS_OF_CREATION">
		<description>
			<p><em>20th-level Bard feature</em></p>
			<p>You have mastered two of the Words of Creation: the word of life and the word of death. You therefore always have the Power Word Heal and Power Word Kill spells prepared. When you cast either spell, you can target a second creature with the spell if that creature is within 10 feet of your first target.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You always have Power Word Heal and Power Word Kill prepared. When you cast either spell, you can target a second creature within 10 feet of your first target.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_2024PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_HEAL" spellcasting="Bard" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_2024PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_KILL" spellcasting="Bard" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Subclasses -->
	<element name="2024 College of Dance" type="Archetype" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_COLLEGE_OF_DANCE">
		<supports>Bard College</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Bards of the College of Dance know that the Words of Creation can't be contained within speech or even song; they are uttered by the movements of celestial bodies and flow through the motions of even the smallest creatures. To these Bards, dance is art freed from the constraints of a single point in space and time; it is meaning unconfined by narrow definitions of words and structures of grammar. The College of Dance practices a way of being in harmony with the ever-whirling cosmos, emphasizing agility, speed, and grace.</p>
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_INSPIRING_MOVEMENT" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_TANDEM_FOOTWORK" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_LEADING_EVASION" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Bards of the College of Dance know that the Words of Creation can't be contained within speech or even song; they are uttered by the movements of celestial bodies and flow through the motions of even the smallest creatures.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_INSPIRING_MOVEMENT" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_TANDEM_FOOTWORK" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_LEADING_EVASION" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Dazzling Footwork" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_DAZZLING_FOOTWORK">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level College of Dance feature</em></p>
			<p>Your practice of dance gives you the ability to gracefully dodge and make agile strikes. While you aren't wearing armor or wielding a Shield, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Unarmored Defense.</strong> Your base Armor Class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Charisma modifier.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Agile Strikes.</strong> When you expend a use of your Bardic Inspiration as part of an action, a Bonus Action, or a Reaction, you can make one Unarmed Strike as part of that action, Bonus Action, or Reaction.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Bardic Damage.</strong> You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack rolls of your Unarmed Strikes, and when you deal damage with an Unarmed Strike, you can deal Bludgeoning damage equal to a roll of your Bardic Inspiration die plus your Dexterity modifier instead of the strike's normal damage. This roll doesn't expend the die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While unarmored and not wielding a shield your AC is {{ac:unarmored defense bard}} and:
			You can use Dexterity for your unarmed attacks and they deal 1d{{bardic inspiration:dice}}+{{dazzling footwork:unarmed:damage}} bludgeoning damage.
			When expending Bardic Inspiration on an action, Bonus Action, or reaction also make one unarmed attack.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense bard" value="10" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense bard" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense bard" value="charisma:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored defense bard" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" alt="Unarmored Defense" />
			<stat name="dazzling footwork:unarmed:damage" value="strength:modifier" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="dazzling footwork:unarmed:damage" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Inspiring Movement" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_INSPIRING_MOVEMENT">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level College of Dance feature</em></p>
			<p>When an enemy you can see ends its turn within 5 feet of an ally of yours who is within 60 feet of you, you can use your Reaction and expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to move up to half your Speed. Then roll your Bardic Inspiration die, and the ally can move up to a number of feet equal to 5 times the number rolled. None of this feature's movement provokes Opportunity Attacks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>When an enemy ends its turn within 5 feet of an ally within 60 feet of you, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to move up to half your Speed. Then roll your Bardic Inspiration die, and the ally can move up to a number of feet equal to 5 times the number rolled. None of this movement provokes Opportunity Attacks.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Tandem Footwork" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_TANDEM_FOOTWORK">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level College of Dance feature</em></p>
			<p>When you roll Initiative, you can spend one use of your Bardic Inspiration if you don't have the Incapacitated condition. When you do so, roll your Bardic Inspiration die, and choose a number of creatures within 60 feet of yourself (you can choose yourself), up to a number equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one creature). Each of them gains a bonus to their Initiative equal to the number rolled.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you roll Initiative, if you don't have the Incapacitated condition, you can spend one use of your Bardic Inspiration. When you do so choose up to {{tandem footwork:number}} creatures within 60 feet of yourself, Each of them gains a bonus to their Initiative equal to the number rolled.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="tandem footwork:number" value="1" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="tandem footwork:number" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Leading Evasion" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_DANCE_LEADING_EVASION">
		<description>
			<p><em>14th-level College of Dance feature</em></p>
			<p>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and you take only half damage if you fail. If any creatures within 5 feet of you are making the same Dexterity saving throw, you can share this benefit with them for that save.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can't use this feature if you have the Incapacitated condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail. You can share this benefit with creatures within 5ft. You can't use this feature if you have the Incapacitated condition.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="2024 College of Glamour" type="Archetype" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_COLLEGE_OF_GLAMOUR">
		<supports>Bard College</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The College of Glamour traces its origins to the beguiling magic of the Feywild. The Bards who study this magic weave threads of beauty and terror into their songs and stories, and the mightiest among them can cloak themselves in otherworldly majesty. Their performances stir up wistful longing for forgotten innocence, evoke unconscious memories of long-held fears, and tug at the emotions of even the most hardhearted listeners.</p>
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_BEGUILING_MAGIC" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_INSPIRATION" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_MAJESTY" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_UNBREAKABLE_MAJESTY" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>The College of Glamour traces its origins to the beguiling magic of the Feywild. The Bards who study this magic weave threads of beauty and terror into their songs and stories.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_BEGUILING_MAGIC" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_INSPIRATION" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_MAJESTY" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_UNBREAKABLE_MAJESTY" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Beguiling Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_BEGUILING_MAGIC">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level College of Glamour feature</em></p>
			<p>You always have the <i>Charm Person</i> and <i>Mirror Image</i> spells prepared.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, immediately after you cast an Enchantment or Illusion spell, you can cause a creature you can see within 60 feet of yourself to make a Wisdom saving throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failed save, the target has the Charmed or Frightened condition (your choice) for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this benefit, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of the feature by expending one use of your Bardic Inspiration (no action required).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest" >
			<description>After casting an Enchantment or Illusion spell, you can cause a creature within 60 feet to make a Wisdom save or be Charmed or Frightened for 1 minute. 
			Once per long rest, or restore by expending Bardic Inspiration.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_2024PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" spellcasting="Bard" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_2024PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" spellcasting="Bard" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mantle of Inspiration" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_INSPIRATION">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level College of Glamour feature</em></p>
			<p>You can weave fey magic into a song or dance to fill others with vigor. As a Bonus Action, you can expend a use of Bardic Inspiration, rolling a Bardic Inspiration die. When you do so, choose a number of other creatures within 60 feet of yourself, up to a number equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one creature). Each of them gains a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to 2 times the number rolled on the Bardic Inspiration die, and then each of them can use its Reaction to move up to its Speed without provoking Opportunity Attacks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You can expend a use of Bardic Inspiration. Choose up to {{mantle of inspiration:uses}} other creatures within 60 feet of yourself. Each of them gains a number of Temporary Hit Points equal to 2 times the number rolled on the Bardic Inspiration die, and then each of them can use its Reaction to move up to its Speed without provoking Opportunity Attacks.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="mantle of inspiration:uses" value="1" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="mantle of inspiration:uses" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mantle of Majesty" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_MAJESTY">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level College of Glamour feature</em></p>
			<p>You always have the <i>Command</i> spell prepared. As a Bonus Action, you cast <i>Command</i> without expending a spell slot, and you take on an unearthly appearance for 1 minute or until your Concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During this time, you can cast <i>Command</i> as a Bonus Action without expending a spell slot. Any creature Charmed by you automatically fails its saving throw against the <i>Command</i> you cast with this feature.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore your use of the feature by expending a spell slot of 3rd level or higher (no action required).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You cast Command without expending a spell slot, and you take on an unearthly appearance for 1 minute or until your Concentration ends. During this time, you can cast Command as a Bonus Action without expending a spell slot. Any creature Charmed by you automatically fails its saving throw against the Command you cast with this feature. You can restore a use by expending a level 3+ spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_2024PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" spellcasting="Bard" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Unbreakable Majesty" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_UNBREAKABLE_MAJESTY">
		<description>
			<p><em>14th-level College of Glamour feature</em></p>
			<p>As a Bonus Action, you can assume a magically majestic presence for 1 minute or until you have the Incapacitated condition. For the duration, whenever any creature hits you with an attack roll for the first time on a turn, the attacker must succeed on a Charisma saving throw against your Spell Save DC, or the attack misses instead, as the creature recoils from your majesty. Once you assume this majestic presence, you can't do so again until you finish a Short Rest or Long Rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You can assume a magically majestic presence for 1 minute or until you have the Incapacitated condition. For the duration, whenever any creature hits you with an attack roll for the first time on a turn, the attacker must succeed on a Charisma saving throw against your Spell Save DC, or the attack misses instead. Once per short or long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<element name="2024 College of Lore" type="Archetype" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_COLLEGE_OF_LORE">
		<supports>Bard College</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Bards of the College of Lore know something about most things, collecting bits of knowledge from sources as diverse as scholarly tomes and peasant tales. Whether singing folk ballads in taverns or elaborate compositions in royal courts, these bards use their gifts to hold audiences spellbound. When the applause dies down, the audience members might find themselves questioning everything they held to be true, from their faith in the priesthood of the local temple to their loyalty to the king.</p>
			<p class="indent">The loyalty of these bards lies in the pursuit of beauty and truth, not in fealty to a monarch or following the tenets of a deity. A noble who keeps such a bard as a herald or advisor knows that the bard would rather be honest than politic.</p>
			<p class="indent">The college's members gather in libraries and sometimes in actual colleges, complete with classrooms and dormitories, to share their lore with one another. They also meet at festivals or affairs of state, where they can expose corruption, unravel lies, and poke fun at self-important figures of authority.</p>
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_CUTTING_WORDS" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_MAGICAL_DISCOVERIES" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_PEERLESS_SKILL" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Bards of the College of Lore know something about most things, collecting bits of knowledge from sources as diverse as scholarly tomes and peasant tales.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_CUTTING_WORDS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_MAGICAL_DISCOVERIES" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_PEERLESS_SKILL" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level College of Lore feature</em></p>
			<p>You gain proficiency with three skills of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Bonus Proficiencies (2024 Bard)" supports="Skill,Bard" number="3" level="3"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Cutting Words" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_CUTTING_WORDS">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level College of Lore feature</em></p>
			<p>You learn to use your wit to supernaturally distract, confuse, and otherwise sap the confidence and competence of others. When a creature that you can see within 60 feet of yourself makes a damage roll or succeeds on an ability check or attack roll, you can take a Reaction to expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration; roll your Bardic Inspiration die, and subtract the number rolled from the creature's roll, reducing the damage or potentially turning the success into a failure.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="Bardic Inspiration" >
			<description>When a creature that you can see within 60 feet of yourself makes a damage roll or succeeds on an ability check or attack roll, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration; and subtract the number rolled from the creature's roll, reducing the damage or potentially turning the success into a failure.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Magical Discoveries" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_MAGICAL_DISCOVERIES">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level College of Lore feature</em></p>
			<p>You learn two spells of your choice. These spells can come from the Cleric, Druid, or Wizard spell list or any combination thereof. A spell you choose must be a cantrip or a spell for which you have spell slots, as shown in the Bard Features table.</p>
			<p class="indent">You always have the chosen spells prepared, and whenever you gain a Bard level, you can replace one of the spells with another spell that meets these requirements.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Magical Discoveries" supports="((Cleric,0)|(Druid,0)|(Wizard,0)||(Cleric,$(spellcasting:slots))|(Druid,$(spellcasting:slots))|(Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)))" number="2" level="6" spellcasting="Bard" prepared="true"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Peerless Skill" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_LORE_PEERLESS_SKILL">
		<description>
			<p><em>14th-level College of Lore feature</em></p>
			<p>When you make an ability check or attack roll and fail, you can expend one use of Bardic Inspiration; roll the Bardic Inspiration die, and add the number rolled to the d20, potentially turning a failure into a success. On a failure, the Bardic Inspiration isn't expended.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you make an ability check or attack roll and fail, you can expend one use of Bardic Inspiration; roll the Bardic Inspiration die, and add the number rolled to the d20, potentially turning a failure into a success. On a failure, the Bardic Inspiration isn't expended.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="2024 College of Valor" type="Archetype" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_COLLEGE_OF_VALOR">
		<supports>Bard College</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Bards of the College of Valor are daring storytellers whose tales keep alive the memory of the great heroes of the past. They travel the land to witness great events firsthand and to ensure that the memory of these events doesn't pass from the world. With their songs, they inspire new generations to reach the same heights of accomplishment as the heroes of old.</p>
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_MARTIAL_TRAINING" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_COMBAT_INSPIRATION" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_BATTLE_MAGIC" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Bards of the College of Valor are daring skalds whose tales keep alive the memory of the great heroes of the past, and thereby inspire a new generation of heroes.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_MARTIAL_TRAINING" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_COMBAT_INSPIRATION" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_BATTLE_MAGIC" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Martial Training" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_MARTIAL_TRAINING">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level College of Valor feature</em></p>
			<p>You gain proficiency with Martial Weapons and armor training with Medium Armor and Shields.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, you can use a Simple or Martial weapon as a spellcasting focus to cast spells from your Bard spell list.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Combat Inspiration" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_COMBAT_INSPIRATION">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level College of Valor feature</em></p>
			<p>You can use your wit to turn the tide of battle. A creature that has a Bardic Inspiration die from you can use it for one of the following effects:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Defense.</strong> When the creature is hit by an attack roll, that creature can use its Reaction to roll the Bardic Inspiration die and add the number rolled to its AC against that attack, potentially causing the attack to miss.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Offense.</strong> Immediately after the creature hits a target with an attack roll, the creature can roll the Bardic Inspiration die and add the number rolled to the attack's damage against the target.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>A creature that has a Bardic Inspiration die from you can use it for:
			Defense, When hit by an attack they can use their reaction to add the bardic inspiration to their AC possibly causing the attack to miss, or 
			Offense, Add the bardic inspiration to damage when hitting with an attack roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_EXTRA_ATTACK">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level College of Valor feature</em></p>
			<p>You can attack twice instead of once whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, you can cast one of your cantrips that has a casting time of an action in place of one of those attacks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can attack twice instead of once whenever you take the Attack action on your turn. 
			Additionally you can cast a cantrip with an action casting time in place of one of those attacks.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="6" bonus="extra attack" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Battle Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="2024 Player's Handbook" id="ID_2024PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_VALOR_BATTLE_MAGIC">
		<description>
			<p><em>14th-level College of Valor feature</em></p>
			<p>After you cast a spell that has a casting time of an action, you can make one attack with a weapon as a Bonus Action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>After you cast a spell that has a casting time of an action, you can make one weapon attack.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

</elements>